<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Food and Drug Administration--Press Releases</title>
		<description>Press releases from FDA</description>
		<link>http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/ContactFDA/StayInformed/RSSFeeds/PressReleases/rss.xml</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 14:28:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
		<webMaster>tina.gilliam@fda.hhs.gov</webMaster>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves new antiplatelet drug used during heart procedure</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved Kengreal (cangrelor), an intravenous antiplatelet drug that prevents formation of harmful blood clots in the coronary arteries, the blood vessels that supply blood to the heart. It is approved for adult patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), a procedure used to open a blocked or narrowed coronary artery to improve blood flow to the heart muscle.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 14:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm452172.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm452172.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA allows marketing of new device to help the blind process visual signals via their tongues</title>
			<description>The Food and Drug Administration today allowed marketing of a new device that when used along with other assistive devices, like a cane or guide dog, can help orient people who are blind by helping them process visual images with their tongues.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 16:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451779.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451779.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA takes action to protect consumers from potentially dangerous counterfeit medicines and devices sold online</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration, in partnership with international regulatory and law enforcement agencies, took action this week against more than 1,050 websites that illegally sell potentially dangerous, unapproved prescription medicines and medical devices to consumers. These actions include the issuance of regulatory warnings to the operators of offending websites and seizure of $81 million worth of illegal medicines and medical devices worldwide.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 11:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451755.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451755.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves SAPIEN 3 THV artificial heart valve</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved the SAPIEN 3 Transcatheter Heart Valve (THV) for patients with a narrowing in the heart's aortic valve, called aortic valve stenosis. Aortic valve stenosis obstructs blood flow from the heart into the aorta, which can lead to serious heart problems. The SAPIEN 3 THV is approved for patients with aortic valve stenosis who are inoperable or at high risk for death or complications associated with open-heart surgery.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 15:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451678.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451678.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The FDA takes step to remove artificial trans fats in processed foods</title>
			<description>Based on a thorough review of the scientific evidence, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration today finalized its determination that partially hydrogenated oils (PHOs), the primary dietary source of artificial trans fat in processed foods, are not “generally recognized as safe” or GRAS for use in human food. Food manufacturers will have three years to remove PHOs from products.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 09:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451237.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451237.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves brain implant to help reduce Parkinson’s disease and essential tremor symptoms</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved the Brio Neurostimulation System, an implantable deep brain stimulation device to help reduce the symptoms of Parkinson’s disease and essential tremor, a movement disorder that is one of the most common causes of tremors. The Brio Neurostimulation System can help some patients when medication alone may not provide adequate relief from symptoms such as walking difficulties, balance problems, and tremors.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 16:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451152.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm451152.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA regulation to help ensure judicious use of antibiotics in food-producing animals</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration announced today the Veterinary Feed Directive (VFD) final rule, an important piece of the agency’s overall strategy to promote the judicious use of antimicrobials in food-producing animals. This strategy will bring the use of these drugs under veterinary supervision so that they are used only when necessary for assuring animal health. The VFD final rule outlines the process for authorizing use of VFD drugs (animal drugs intended for use in or on animal feed that require the supervision of a licensed veterinarian) and provides veterinarians in all states with a framework for authorizing the use of medically important antimicrobials in feed when needed for specific animal health purposes.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 09:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm448446.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm448446.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves Rapamune to treat LAM, a very rare lung disease</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved Rapamune (sirolimus), to treat lymphangioleiomyomatosis (LAM), a rare, progressive lung disease that primarily affects women of childbearing age. This is the first drug approved to treat the disease.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 16:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm448523.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm448523.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves two therapies to treat IBS-D</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved Viberzi (eluxadoline) and Xifaxan (rifaximin), two new treatments, manufactured by two different companies, for irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea (IBS-D) in adult men and women.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 16:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm448328.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm448328.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA proposes rule to collect antimicrobial sales and distribution data by animal species</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration proposed a rule today that would require animal drug sponsors of all antimicrobials sold or distributed for use in food-producing animals to obtain estimates of sales by major food-producing species (cattle, swine, chickens and turkeys). The additional data would improve understanding of how antimicrobials are sold or distributed for use in major food-producing animals and help the FDA further target its efforts to ensure judicious use of medically important antimicrobials.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 09:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm447244.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm447244.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA releases draft guidance on animal drug compounding from bulk drug substances</title>
			<description>As part of its overall efforts to address compounded drugs, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration today released a draft “Guidance for Industry (GFI) #230, Compounding Animal Drugs from Bulk Drug Substances.”</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 10:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm447159.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm447159.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves spinal cord stimulation system that treats pain without tingling sensation</title>
			<description>Today the U.S. Food and Drug Administration approved the Senza spinal cord stimulation (SCS) system (Senza System) as an aid in the management of chronic intractable pain of the trunk and/or limbs, including pain associated with failed back surgery syndrome, low back pain and leg pain. The Senza System can reduce pain without producing a tingling sensation called paresthesia by providing high frequency stimulation (at 10 KHz) and low stimulation amplitudes.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 17:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm446354.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm446354.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves additional antibacterial treatment for plague</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved Avelox (moxifloxacin) to treat patients with plague, a rare and potentially fatal bacterial infection. The agency approval for plague includes use of the drug for the treatment of pneumonic plague (infection of the lungs), and septicemic plague (infection of the blood). Avelox is also approved for prevention of plague in adult patients.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 14:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm446283.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm446283.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves Raplixa to help control bleeding during surgery</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved Raplixa (fibrin sealant [human]), the first spray-dried fibrin sealant approved by the agency. It is used to help control bleeding during surgery.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 17:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm445247.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm445247.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA issues proposed rule to address data gaps for certain active ingredients in health care antiseptics</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today issued a proposed rule requesting additional scientific data to support the safety and effectiveness of certain active ingredients used in health care antiseptics marketed under the over-the-counter drug monograph.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 08:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm445002.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm445002.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves treatment for fat below the chin</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved Kybella (deoxycholic acid), a treatment for adults with moderate-to-severe fat below the chin, known as submental fat. Using Kybella for the treatment of fat outside of the submental area is not approved and is not recommended.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 13:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm444978.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm444978.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA approves first generic Abilify to treat mental illnesses</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration today approved the first generic versions of Abilify (aripiprazole). Generic aripiprazole is an atypical antipsychotic drug approved to treat schizophrenia and bipolar disorder.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 14:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm444862.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm444862.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FDA enters consent decree with Medtronic, Inc.</title>
			<description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration announced today the filing of a consent decree against Medtronic, Inc., and two of the company’s officers—S. Omar Ishrak and Thomas M. Tefft —for repeatedly failing to correct violations, related to the manufacture of Synchromed II Implantable Infusion Pump Systems, medical devices that deliver medication to treat primary or metastatic cancer, chronic pain and severe spasticity. These violations occurred at the company’s Neuromodulation facilities in Columbia Heights, Minnesota, where the devices are manufactured.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<link>http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm444690.htm</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm444690.htm</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>